# **Rachel Dowdy**

Newly trained data analyst and web builder! My previous career was in music education, but from that position, I gained experience in accounting, fundraising, data engineering, communication, maintaining inventory and orders, and I am a people person! I have always had a very strong eye for detail, and mind for science and logic. I also love bringing people together.

9801 Boulder Hill Street, San Antonio, TX 78250 (210)415-5487 racheladowdy@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Northside ISD,** Folks Middle School — Orchestra Director

July 2017 - November 2021

Many jobs, including inventory, accounting, data engineering, administrative duties, lesson planning, newsletter creation, department event calendar management, source private lesson teachers, event planning, mass communication in a 200+ student program

#### **Basis.ed**, BASIS San Antonio Medical Center — Orchestra/Choir Director

July 2015 - 2017

Recruit and grow program; build library; event planning and logistics; lesson planning

#### **Terra Nova Violins**, San Antonio — Studio Administrator

May 2013 - July 2014

Manage studio schedule; recruit students and match with appropriate instrument teacher; mass communication; manage scheduling and appointments; clean and decorate studios; customer service

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Rice University via UTSA**, Online Data Analytics Bootcamp — *Certificate soon!*

November 2021 - June 2022 (CURRENT)

Data Analytics Bootcamp: VBA, Excel macros, Python, Jupyter Notebook, GitHub, Matplotlib, pandas, Leaflet, JavaScript, HTML-5, Bootstrap, CSS, APIs, Flask

### **University of Texas at San Antonio** — *Music, with focus in Education*

August 2008 - May 2013

#### **PROJECTS**

# Paranormal Traffic Webpage — SQL, Flask, html, css, Python, Javascript, API, Leaflet

Created a webpage that can access the sourced data, which has three interactive maps that show density of the three topics we chose. Group project.

https://github.com/JWatson1102/Project 3

#### **Pymaceuticals Analysis** — *Jupyter Notebook*, *Python*, *Matplotlib*

Created a JupyterNotebook detailing data concerning lab mice and subsequent tumor sizes in relation to medications administered using statistics and data visualizations.

https://github.com/radowtay/matplotlib-challenge

# **IMDB Movie Data** — APIs, Jupyter Notebook, Python, Matplotlib

Created theories concerning dataset, then used analytical tools to develop a presentation showing data renderings of our findings. Group project.

https://github.com/radowtay/Project-1

# **Weather Findings Webpage** — *Jupyter Notebook, pandas, html, Bootstrap*

Used images from a previous project and created a webpage to detail and layout the findings from that project.

https://github.com/radowtay/Web-Design-Challenge